<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 21:42:56 -0400</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>School Pizza</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/14/school-pizza.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/06/14/school-pizza.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One day, when I’m wealthy beyond my wildest dreams and am looking for any excuse to occupy my time, I’m going to open a little restaurant or food truck called “School Pizza.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu will be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cheese pizza rectangle slice: $2.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pepperoni pizza rectangle slice: $2.25&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whole-fat chocolate milk carton: $1.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/pizza.webp&quot; alt=&quot;What a proper school pizza tray looks like, shamelessly stolen from photographer unknown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combo: $4.00 (Includes rectangle pizza slice, carton of chocolate milk, side of corn, and peaches for desert. All combos are served in a segmented tray.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours: 11am - Sold Out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll make a million bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hospital Pro-Tips</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/13/hospital-pro-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/06/13/hospital-pro-tips.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s unfortunate that I have had to spend so much of my life in the hospital so far, but as a result I am now a seasoned pro, and have some tips to share in case you ever find yourself in a similar predicament. These are going to be slightly “out there” in terms of advice, but these are the things I wish others had told me about rather than having to figure them out on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a razor. Keeping to a daily routine and maintaining a clean appearance is the key difference between feeling like a human and feeling like a zombie in the hospital. For me, as soon as I get two or three days growth on my beard, I immediately start feeling worse. Hospitals offer disposable razors and shaving cream, but they are not especially sharp. For best results, smuggle in your own razor (electric razors are great if you can’t stand at a sink after surgery). You should also take time for your other daily hygiene tasks, including brushing your teeth and washing your face. Your nurses won’t remind you to do any of this, you have to make the effort to remember and carve out time to get it done. Trust me, it will make all the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid the gown as long as you can. The gowns are embarrassing, and they lead to the feelings of zombietude I mentioned above. They are never long enough, they never fully cover your backside no matter how many times you tie them, and you will never feel like your best self as long as you wear one. Sometimes they are unavoidable and hospital staff will insist (especially for surgery), but if you can get by wearing loose clothing like sweat pants and baggy t-shirts, those are the way to go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keeping gadgets powered is the name of the game. Time doesn’t really exist in the hospital. You may sleep all day, and you may stay up all night. To keep yourself sane, you will need some form of distraction, whether it be your phone, tablet, ereader, laptop, or other electronic gizmos. It’s also your lifeline to messaging and calling your loved ones, should you need anything or should they be wondering how you’re doing. Juggling battery charges between multiple devices can be difficult, especially if you are stuck in bed and can’t handle things yourself. My two pieces of advice (for now): skip the power bricks and go straight for the wall outlet, and don’t be afraid to ask your nurses to do you a favor and plug in the brick in an empty outlet behind the hospital bed. While it might be the case that you (or they) aren’t supposed to do that, I’ve yet to have anyone kick up too much of a fuss about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shave your body hair before you go in, if you can. This mainly applies to the especially hairy among us. You will have various stickers covering your chest, arms, you name it, and medical staff are more than happy to rip them off for you quite painfully. Don’t give them the satisfaction, trim your hair ahead of time if you have enough advanced notice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep a food and drink stash. Food arrives at odd times in the hospital. In my experience, breakfast is usually 7:30am, lunch is 11:30am, and dinner is 4:30pm. You will almost certainly get hungry again later in the evening. Not only that, but you need to stay up on your fluids, and you don’t want to keep bugging the nurses to bring you more (you’ll also probably just be limited to water or whatever off-brand version of Sprite the hospital offers). For this reason, keep a small stash of snacks and drinks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember that you know more about your body than your doctors (even though they know more about human bodies than you do). The medical staff in the hospitals I’ve been to have all been incredible. They are experts in their field, and know more about the inner workings of the human body than you ever will. That said, you are an expert when it comes to your particular body, and will know more about how it specifically functions than they do. If something feels wrong, or slightly off, or if you get a gut feeling that they are suggesting something that might be counter-productive for your well-being, speak up and advocate for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cropping videos in VLC to 3:2 for the the Framework display</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/framework-vlc-crop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/framework-vlc-crop.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a little pro-tip I discovered in VLC, which will allow you to crop your videos to a 3:2 aspect ratio that matches the display in the Framework laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works best on videos that are either 16:9 or 4:3 aspect ratio to begin with. For really wide theatrical videos (like 2.35:1) you will lose too much of the picture for this to be worth it, but for videos that are vaguely Framework-shaped, it might be worth shaving off a bit of the content so you can use every square inch of your display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, in VLC, go to Preferences → Show settings → All, then navigate to Video → Custom crop ratios list, and add the text “3:2”. When you’re done, click Save.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, when you load a video, you can now select to crop to 3:2 from the Video → Crop menu, and when you go fullscreen it will use the full display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/framework-vlc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: I originally posted this to the Framework community via &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.frame.work/t/pro-tip-cropping-videos-in-vlc-to-take-advantage-of-the-framework-display/67771&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Friend is Giving Me a Kidney</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/13/micah.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/03/13/micah.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldkidneyday.org/&quot;&gt;World Kidney Day&lt;/a&gt;, and I can think of no better time to share some very happy news: I’ll be receiving a kidney in (or around) April! And even better, someone very important to me is making it all happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been told earlier this year that I had a potential donor stepping through the process to make sure they were a good fit for a kidney donation. Then, a few weeks ago, I was told that the donor had made it all the way through the arduous process, and was cleared for donation. No one had told me that they were considering a donation, so I honestly had no idea who it might be. Finally, last week, they shared the name of my donor with me. I cannot express how thankful I am to share the news that I will be receiving a kidney from my long-time friend, Micah Ilbery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve known Micah for over a decade now, if memory serves me correctly. Back when I was heavily involved with elementary OS I knew him from that community. He called into the podcast I co-hosted with Dane Henson a few times, and since then we’ve stayed in touch in various ways (especially, in recent years, Mastodon). It’s incredible to know he’s willing to do something so remarkable for me, even though we’ve never even technically met in-person yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micah is an absolutely wonderful human being, and there’s so much more I could say about this journey, but I’ll let him tell the rest of the story if and when he ever decides to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’ll be having his surgery in a few weeks, then I’ll follow soon after. I’m looking forward to visiting him and his family a bit before. It will be so amazing to finally meet “in real life” (as if the internet isn’t “real life” - my internet friend is giving me a kidney, for goodness sake!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Micah, for being so generous and selfless, and for giving me a more normal life and many healthy, happy years to come. And thank you Cheryl, my incredible cousin who generously donated a kidney to me last year (I’m still so sorry that one didn’t work out like we hoped). I’ll never be able to thank either of them enough!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breakdown</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/01/breakdown.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/01/01/breakdown.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m listening to the album “Plans” by Death Cab for Cutie, and the song “Brothers on a hotel bed” floored me. It’s not because I feel like I’m getting old (necessarily), or that things have grown stale between me and my partner; rather, the line “he lives inside someone he does not recognize when he catches his reflection on accident.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was me. In many ways, it still is. I’m living inside someone I don’t recognize. I’m not myself, and I haven’t been myself for about a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure the cause. Honestly, I think it’s a whole bunch of stuff piling on at the same time: almost dying in the hospital, dealing with a failed kidney transplant, transitioning into a new lifestyle that revolves around dialysis, moving into a new home while at the same time helping my parents move out of my childhood home (and getting rid of lots of stuff with sentimental or nostalgic value), and more. It was a lot, all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that I’m now permanently on a low dose of prednisone, which my body does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; respond to well. It makes me cranky, irritable, and generally less forgiving, all traits I am ashamed of and actively worked towards curbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I think I finally have made peace with everything, and have started to turn things around as of late. There wasn’t a big a-ha moment or anything. Honestly, the thing that has helped me most is going back through the posts here on this blog, and re-reading the things that past me has written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading is a uniquely effective method of living in someone else’s mind, and it turns out that it’s also effective at remembering what it feels like inside your own mind when you’ve forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m finally starting to feel like me again, slowly. I hope that others haven’t noticed too much irritability or unkindness on my part, but if you have, please know that I am deeply sorry, and am working to get back to my old self (warts and all).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Goals</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/31/no-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/31/no-goals.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, for as long as I can remember, I’ve started the new year off with a set of goals, detailing what I wanted to achieve over the 365 days to follow. Most of the goals are hopeful. They are reflections of a change or maturation of values, or represent the steps necessary to get to a new and improved position in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, try as I might to put them down, I cannot really think of any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried many times, my fingers hovering over the keys on my keyboard, itching to jot down my innermost desires. At the same time, I find myself squinting and staring off into the middle distance, trying to formulate a list of achievable and measurable goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I still can’t think of any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a couple weak ones written down, but I don’t feel strongly about them. The truth is, I have no real skin in the game about whether or not they are accomplished or not. If they are, that would be cool, but I won’t feel like I failed to live up to my potential if they don’t get crossed off before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I wondered if this is a form of depression. I’m not sure if I’m depressed, or just had a bit of a mental breakdown this year (more on that later). Or maybe I’m growing older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I think about it, I don’t think it’s any of those things. Really, I think it’s a sign that I’m pretty content with how my life already is. There are things I’d tweak here and there, but I’m a happy guy, and am pleased with how things are at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is also a result of wisdom that I have gained over the past year. It’s strange embarking on another year without a new set of goals. But if I know anything, it’s that things will change, nothing will go quite to plan, and the year will be vastly different (and hopefully, better) than I expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a great new year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Environmentalism and Free Culture</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/30/environmentalism-and-free-culture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/30/environmentalism-and-free-culture.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why one might be drawn to free software, open hardware, and expanding the right to repair. I have several reasons that stick out particularly strongly in my mind, but one of the greatest reasons is environmental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the tech we use every day, the most significant personal environmental impact you can have is to avoid buying replacement devices unnecessarily, and keeping older devices up and running for as long as possible. The longer we can keep devices out of landfills and e-waste centers, the bigger the overall win for the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I’m sometimes a bit disappointed by the ongoing environmental efforts in the open source world. I was recently made aware of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eco.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE Eco project&lt;/a&gt;, which has laudable goals. The project is designed to make developers aware of the energy impact of the applications they create, and try to limit power consumption in order to not only extend battery life for your devices, but also decrease the overall power consumption of your computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bit skeptical about the impact that can be had here (most applications aren’t especially power-intensive and, at least in my mind, any significant power savings would need to happen either at the OS or hardware level), but I like the thought behind it all the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some areas where FOSS does make an environmental difference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It allows users to keep older devices up and running for longer, either by allowing updates beyond when the original manufacturer intended to support the system, or by allowing you to use lower-power alternatives for the operating system to keep older systems in use longer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open source software is, generally speaking, more interoperable, so you don’t have to use a specific device from one manufacturer to communicate or work in conjunction with a device from a different manufacturer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By combining efforts and working collaboratively, fewer resources are used by companies to create multiple tools that have the same/duplicate functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I don’t think that this is something that free software developers think about quite enough. Proprietary OSes and hardware, such as Apple’s iPadOS and macOS coupled with their devices running the newer M-series chips, are able to really take advantage of the hardware and manage the power to give an incredible amount of performance and an outstanding battery life. There can sometimes be advantages to that model. You can also tell how much the folks at Apple are thinking about energy use and power management; when you open the Activity Monitor, alongside the usual tables for memory usage and disk access, there’s a tab for energy used by each application. It’s not an afterthought, but rather a focus to keep users aware of the impact of the individual applications they are using, and to keep app developers as competitive and energy-minded as possible. I hope that, moving forward, we see more and more power management optimizations at the OS level, and more hardware like the M-series chips that can be very powerful at lower power consumption than other chips, but that are more open than the M1 so everyone can take advantage of them. The Ryzen 9 series from AMD has me especially hopeful, and the new Snapdragon processors could be good too, provided Qualcom follows through and manages to make good on their promises to add Linux compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Physical Digital</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/27/physical-digital.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/27/physical-digital.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a minimalist, I’ve been on a journey of letting go of things that don’t add value to my life. In most cases, I have been as ruthless as necessary, but I have had a more difficult time when it comes to books. I’ve primarily been using ereaders as my medium of choice for the past decade, but there are some books from my teenage years that were foundational to who I am today, and parting with them feels almost like a crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were books that had less sentimental value to me; those I parted with quite easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some books that I feel far too strongly about, and still regularly peruse or get value out of. Those I won’t be parting with, so those are also an easy decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a third category of books that I’m having to learn to let go of: books that originally started out as a digital copy, but that I liked so much I picked up a physical copy for my collection. These are books that I love, but I don’t really have an attachment to their &lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; form. I’ve never technically &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; the dead tree copies in the first place. The original copies are dear to me, and will continue to remain in my digital library, but the physical copy has only ever really been “nice to look at.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best example of these I have are Lawrence Lessig’s books. I devoured them as a teenager, learning about digital rights and how technology shapes the world. I believe I read them all on the harsh LCD screen of a first or second generation iPad. I’ve never read their physical forms, but I bought them second-hand from an online bookstore around a decade ago just so they could live on my shelf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, there’s the exact opposite issue: things that began their life in more of a physical form, but whose digital version is the one that provides value today. This applies to certain books (which were honestly fairly easy to part with and replace with digital versions), but the better example of his issue is in a different medium altogether: video games. As a child, I adored my video games, especially the Nintendo 64 I received for Christmas when I was six (for the record it was the Donkey Kong 64 edition, in transparent jungle green, and of course had the iconic yellow DK64 cartridge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as an adult, I continue to play DK64 all the time. It, and others like Banjo-Kazooie, as well as a collection of SNES games, are still my all-time favorites, and I love playing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can’t think of the last time I actually connected the original console to a television to play them. I much prefer using a modern, comfortable, wireless controller, and find that emulators provide an absolutely lovely experience. I can play things everywhere I go, on any device I want. And they look better than they ever have (although there’s something to say about the glow of an old CRT display).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have trouble parting with the consoles. I mean, &lt;em&gt;Santa&lt;/em&gt; brought me that Nintendo 64! But what value are they, really, beyond very happy memories? The games, the things I still value, have a new life as a digital file that I play on any device I please. Maybe one day I’ll show my kids my old consoles, but that’s really just a novelty, and furthermore, I don’t think they’ll care that much. Maybe they’ll love DK64 as much as I do. But I don’t think they’ll give a rip about the green plastic box from my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the passage of time, things change. Sometimes I think we place value on the physicality of things, even when the thing we appreciate was never really a physical thing in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time to let the vessels go; it was never about the machine, it was always about the ghost inside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love Things</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/love-things.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/love-things.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that &lt;a href=&quot;http://theminimalists.com/&quot;&gt;the Minimalists&lt;/a&gt; repeat constantly is “love people, use things (because the opposite never works).” I don’t think I agree, even as a minimalist who is increasingly apt to get rid of the things I own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most things we own are either either necessities, or things that aren’t exactly life-changing, but there are a few things that I own that I do genuinely love. They add value to my life. There’s something about them that makes me feel comfort or pride, or some other feeling. Maybe it’s the way the handle feels in my hand, the weight of it, the unique form it takes, or something altogether different that makes it special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a danger in becoming attaching to stuff, and letting things fill the empty spaces in our homes and in our lives. Consumerism and overconsumption are big problems facing the world today. We throw away so much stuff, much of which is still completely usable, with our planet and environment taking the brunt of the punishment for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yet, I still think it’s okay to love things. Not everything. Not even most things. But some, selective, special things are okay to love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building things with care and attention, pouring ourselves into the things we create, those are ways for us to show love to our fellow people, to connect with others who we might never meet, and is also part of the legacy we leave behind. I was here; look what I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So go ahead, love people, and love things. Just love as many people as you possibly can, and as few items as you can get away with to live a full and satisfying life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Holidays Suck</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/25/holidays-suck.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/25/holidays-suck.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not a fan of holidays, in a way that’s difficult for me to articulate. In theory, I’m a big fan. I enjoy taking time away from work. I’m thankful that others get to do the same, and either spend time with their families, or spend time reflecting and relaxing. I would be sad if people didn’t get the chance to do that periodically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But selfishly, I don’t like when the world takes the same day off (or, and most especially, an entire week).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy my day-to-day life. I love waking up to a fresh batch of blog posts and social posts to read, new podcasts to listen to, new videos to watch. There’s always something interesting or novel to enjoy. Except around the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also love cooking at home, but I don’t like feeling that I have no other choice. I enjoy being able to grab a quick bite to eat when I’m out and about, if I want. If I’m not feeling well on a particular day, or just don’t have it in me to cook something, it’s nice being able to let others do that for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that is to say, I really love that holidays exist, and I think they’re a good thing. I wouldn’t really do away with them, even if I had the chance. But just because I think something is good for the world, doesn’t mean I have to individually like it. All I know is that while I’m glad the world slows down around Christmas, I’m personally looking forward to January 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Long Con</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/23/the-long-con.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/23/the-long-con.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to most things, I’m an extraordinarily patient person. I don’t get fussy when it takes too long for a restaurant to send out the food I’ve ordered, or when I have to wait for hours in a cramped sitting area at a doctor’s office. But despite my generally patient nature, I’m always impatient when it comes to the future. I want it now. I want to be living in the world of tomorrow, today. It just can’t come fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m honestly not sure why. For the past decade (at least), I’ve felt that the world was generally getting worse with each passing year. But yet I still feel this way. I guess it’s a natural inclination towards optimism that I struggle to turn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I have to remind myself that important things take time. It’s easy to rush things out prematurely, without taking the care to consider the impact, or the unintended consequences. It’s easy to rush things out half-baked, before they’re truly ready. Good things take time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news, though, is that we have the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to spend my formative years during the period of tech history where things were changing rapidly. Every few months there was some exciting, life-changing gizmo. The DVD, the iPod, the portable media player, the PDA, the netbook, the smartphone, and a steady but impressive evolution of laptops from bulky, awkward slabs to sleek and lightweight mobile machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was exhilarating, and it often felt like it was impossible to keep up with the pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first used Linux back in 2008, on Ubuntu 8.10 “Intrepid Ibex”. Coming from Windows XP, it was almost mind blowing. But as I continued to watch the tech world unfold, it felt like we were always trying to catch up. We were always one step behind the “big guys.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, something funny happened; the innovation slowed. The free software alternatives got better and better. They started supporting more hardware. They gained more features. The user experience improved. The visual design made leaps. In many cases, it far surpassed its competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happened because the move fast, keep iterating, keep growing phase is just that; it’s a phase. Eventually, everything runs out of steam. And on the scale on decades, centuries, and millinea, the five or six years of catch-up are utterly meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a quote from the movie “Spotlight” that sticks with me: “The church,” it is said, “thinks in centuries.” It’s less concerned with the immediate present, and more concerned with how it’s positioning itself for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a poor example because in this instance the Catholic church was covering up hundreds of horrific sexual abuse cases and protecting the abusers, but the sentiment of moving slow and thinking on larger time scales is nevertheless prescient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now know, roughly, what a computer is. We are starting to have a pretty good idea of what a phone is. I suspect that in the future we may figure out that they are the same thing. The innovation hasn’t stopped, but it has plateaued. We’re now in a position where free software can catch up to, and surpass, the alternatives (and, in many cases, already has). And the great thing about free software is, once that happens, with proper maintenance and care, it really can stand the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Codeberg</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/22/codeberg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/22/codeberg.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past long while I’ve been moving all my personal projects from GitHub to Codeberg. I’ve decided to do this for numerous reasons: some ideological, some practical, and some personal. I thought it might be worthwhile to list them here, in case others are curious about the viability of such a move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of reasons, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It simply doesn’t make sense to build free software on a non-free platform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By continuing to use GitHub, I am be driving contributors and technical users to the platform, which allows Microsoft to maintain its market dominance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conversely, by leaving GitHub for another platform, I am demonstrating that it’s a perfectly reasonable and possible thing to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microsoft’s headstrong push into using more and more AI on the platform is contributing to the global climate crisis (among other issues).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GitHub has a “maximalist” interface, and I find that I can never actually locate what I’m looking for. Codeberg’s (or rather, Forejo) interface is minimal and much easier to navigate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeberg is actively working on ActivityPub support, and is a participant in the Fediverse. It also provides excellent support for RSS, so folks can follow your work without needing an account or having to use proprietary software.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeberg is a nonprofit that is operated by its members, with each member having voting rights and a say in the direction (of which I am now one).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeberg is built on top of Forejo, which is open-source and battle tested, and it contributes upstream to the project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more people who use a wide variety of services, the richer and more diverse the ecosystem. If one code hosting service goes down, it’s easier to simply migrate to another (admittedly, the distributed nature of git makes this generally true regardless of the repository you use).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This represents a fresh start for my projects. Over the past decade I’ve learned a tremendous amount about what it takes to make software, and some of the best practices for doing so. While I’m still far from perfect, and will never be a “professional developer”, having a place to start fresh and do things semi-correctly is nice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is less scrutiny there, which feels more freeing. The things I do feel less visible, somehow, which puts less pressure on me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It allows me to have some level of separation in my work. GitHub is where my work happens for my employer, and Codeberg is where my work happens outside of work hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say I am completely off of GitHub. I plan to continue using it for my personal website (it is always ethical to use the billion dollar company’s bandwidth rather instead of the smaller org with fewer resources to spare). In order to publish my apps on Flathub, it’s necessary to maintain a presence there. But for most day-to-day work, you can find me here: https://codeberg.org/nathandyer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vocal is End-of-Life</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/26/end-of-vocal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/11/26/end-of-vocal.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have made the decision to officially end development of Vocal, the podcast app that I created and have been (nominally) maintaining since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the year I gave myself an ultimatum: either release a new version before the end of the year, or wind down the project. I figured if I couldn’t get a release out the door within a year, then I had no business maintaining it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like it’s important to know the right time to start a project, it’s equally important to know when to end it gracefully. For Vocal, that time should have been around five years ago. I’ve been in denial about it for a while, just because it’s so important to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the project as a sophomore in college. I had never really written a GUI application, and had no idea what I was doing, but I was in love with podcasts and felt that we were sorely missing a decent podcast client for Linux. In the evenings I would sit and study the Vala documentation, look at source code for other apps, and read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.elementary.io/develop/&quot;&gt;elementary OS developer documentation&lt;/a&gt;. I was a huge fan of elementary OS, and thought that their Granite framework was the future, so targeting Vocal for that platform was an obvious decision. With time and lots of effort, it started to come together. I was also fortunate to have a ton of encouragement and support from Danielle Foré and Cassidy James Blaede, as well as my podcast co-host Dane Henson, UX help from Sam Hewitt, and code and icon contributions from lots of different and amazing folks from around the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know anything about what it means to be a good maintainer. I wasn’t thinking of Vocal as a project, so much as a product. I was young and inexperienced. As the years progressed I learned more about what it takes to foster a community around a project, how to keep it healthy, and how to be a better maintainer. But unfortunately, Vocal never saw any of that progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason why is that I got sick; sicker than I really ever acknowledged or was willing to come to terms with. Living in kidney failure, I don’t have the time or energy it takes to maintain such a large, intricate application with so many moving parts. I also work full-time for a job that I deeply, deeply care about, and it takes precedence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there’s also the fact that getting Vocal into shape again has been a huge undertaking, because I’ve let it fall into disrepair so badly. I’ve spent hours upon hours, especially over the past summer, porting it to the latest version of GTK and Adwaita, hoping to have it ready for a launch this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do I now, all of a sudden, decide to end things? Because truthfully, Vocal is no longer needed. I lived in denial because I still felt that Vocal had a place in the world. It had features that other apps were missing. It supported things that other apps didn’t. And I had even bigger plans for what it could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the truth is, &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.gnome.org/Podcasts/&quot;&gt;GNOME Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.kde.org/kasts/&quot;&gt;Kasts&lt;/a&gt; are both now fully-featured podcast apps, and provide a better experience than Vocal. GNOME Podcasts now has support for searching podcast directories, support for marking episodes as read and unread is in the nightly build, and it’s way more responsive and stable than Vocal ever was. I use it every day, and love it more and more with each update. It lets you import/export OPML files, and aside from a missing queue (which I expect will be coming in the future), it has roughly all the same features as Vocal. I hope that one day it will adopt some of the better features from the Podcasting 2.0 spec, especially chapter support, but as it stands it’s a very usable app. I wish them, as well as the Kasts maintainers, the very best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I do, however, hope that some day the GNOME Podcasts project considers changing its icon - I for one have never listened to a podcast on casette, and find the metaphor baffling.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be archiving everything and working to get the existing Vocal Flatpak marked end-of-life as soon as I can, but I wanted to make the announcement first. I’m sorry I didn’t end the project sooner and give Vocal the dignified end that it deserved. Thanks to everyone who ever contributed to the project or donated to keep it running, and everyone who used it over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Secret Trick to Make Water Bottles Stay Clean for Days (It&apos;s Ice)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/10/09/water-bottles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/10/09/water-bottles.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For ages I’ve wondered how some people seem to carry around the same water bottle with them, day after day, everywhere they go. Any time I’ve attempted the same, my water bottle would inevitably develop a funky smell, usually before the end of the day but always before day #2. More than that, it turned into a veritable petri dish, surely a menace not only to my health but the health of the population at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, a good wash would fix the issue immediately, but I never really saw that people were washing their bottles throughout the day, or even nightly. How were they pulling off this astonishing feat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret to making a water bottle stretch for days and days on a single wash is to use ice. Having a bottle with good insulation, double-walled if you can spring for it, doesn’t hurt, but without ice even that can only get you so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as you let it run out of ice and the temperature rises from chilly to lukewarm, the gig is up. You have lost. Return the bottle to the nearest dishwasher or sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you keep it cold, and replenish the ice daily, you too can achieve these feats of magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But please still give your bottle the ole sniff test on a regular basis, and wash as soon as it’s iffy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asahi Linux with GNOME As a Daily Driver in Late 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/10/08/asahi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/10/08/asahi.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago I decided to purchase a MacBook Air M2, with the specific purpose of running Asahi Fedora Remix. I chose this particular model because it’s the newest chipset that is supported by Asahi, and Best Buy was having a $200 off sale on them, presumably before Apple announces a new slate of laptops and stops offering the aging M2-based systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/macbook-air-asahi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were several things I really loved about the system (battery life was astounding, the trackpad was marvelous, and the display was beautiful), but ultimately I made the decision to return it; the experience just wasn’t what I needed for a daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I plan to answer the questions I had before purchasing the system, and either couldn’t find, or had to really work to track down the info. To be clear: I do think that it’s usable enough for some people to use as a daily driver; it was just more than I was willing to put up with, especially for the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t really cover things that are mentioned in the Asahi wiki/knowledgebase. Certain hardware features are not yet supported; covering them here would be redundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important note: I am a die-hard GNOME user, so my experience was that of someone using GNOME Shell and almost exclusively libadwaita-based apps. I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; install plasma-desktop for the sake of comparison; some things worked better there (mainly fractional scaling), but overall there wasn’t a ton of difference either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;things-that-were-broken&quot;&gt;Things That Were Broken&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night Light&lt;/strong&gt;: with the display driver that is used by default in Asahi Fedora Remix, Night Light is completely unsupported. I rely on this feature heavily for visual comfort.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video hardware acceleration&lt;/strong&gt; isn’t working yet. I knew this going in, but the prevailing public opinion seemed to be “the software renderer is so fast you’ll never notice it.” Suffice to say, I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; notice it. 1080p video playback was fine, but it struggled to play 4K content smoothly, and playing 4K content while also trying to tonemap HDR to SDR (something that is necessary with HDR not yet being supported by Linux) slowed the machine down to a crawl, while also making it get worryingly hot to the touch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High RAM usage&lt;/strong&gt;. On my other daily driver, I often see RAM hovering at around the ~4GB mark. On this system, it was almost always right at the 8GB threshold, with the swap use continually climbing into the several GB range as well. I think this &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be related to using the experimental fractional scaling (necessary for this display), but the performance overall just was not what I had hoped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DRM playback&lt;/strong&gt; does not work. I almost didn’t catch this because I almost never watch anything that requires DRM, but one day while trying to watch an episode of &lt;em&gt;The Price is Right&lt;/em&gt; on my lunch break, I realized that it was failing to play the video because DRM wasn’t enabled. When I checked Firefox, the option wasn’t there in the usual spot. I installed Chromium for giggles, and likewise, it was not an option. I suspect it’s an issue with aarch64 not being supported by Widevine on Linux, but I haven’t done any further homework than that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apps that use &lt;strong&gt;WebkitGTK&lt;/strong&gt; were terribly sluggish. I’m not sure why, but any app that used WebkitGTK (I noticed this most in GNOME Web/Epiphany and Newsflash) were slow and stuttery, especially when the web view was visible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Random graphical artifacts. This was hard to track down, but I noticed random black boxes, rendering oddities, and in an especially humorous turn, text that would occasional render in “Mocking Spongebob Mode” (yOu kNoW WhEn tEXt lOOkS lIKE thiS). It was most noticeable with libadwaita-based apps, which is almost every app I use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting up &lt;strong&gt;disk encryption&lt;/strong&gt; is a headache that you probably won’t do. I generally rely on encryption for every digital device I use, but was put off by the headache of trying to set up a LUKS-encrypted boot partition for Asahi. It sounds possible if you monkey around with USB-based install solutions and custom partitioning, but life is too short for me to get that figured out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-linux-handle-the-notch&quot;&gt;How Does Linux Handle the Notch?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It handles it by pretending it’s not there! It just crops that portion of the display, giving you a perfect 16:10 aspect ratio, with no notch visible. There is a kernel option you can set to &lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt; the notch, but I recommend against it if you are a GNOME user, as you would lose the clock/notification area (or at the least, would have to install an extension to relocate its position).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-is-the-battery-life&quot;&gt;How Is The Battery Life?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazing! Depending on how much I babied it, I would almost always get 8 hours, and would often get as much as 12. The battery life on macOS is better, no question, but it’s not so much lower in Linux that you will be tempted back to macOS for the battery life alone (probably).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall-thoughts&quot;&gt;Overall Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The M-based MacBooks are really spectacular machines. The build quality is exceptional, the battery life is remarkable, and overall I can’t say enough great things about them. They are likely not, however, the best choice for someone whose daily driver is Linux, or who develops for a Linux-based platform such as GNOME.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
